Breton mss. II, 1946-2010 LMC 1125
Lilly Library
Breton mss. II
1946-2010
Lilly Library
Breton, Jean
LMC 1125
6 folios
1 Box 1 standard
2 bound
The Breton mss. II, 1946-, consist of literary works acquired through Jean Breton, proprietor of the firm of Librairie Saint-Germain-Des-Pres in Paris. Some of the writings are accompanied by letters and related materials.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Jean Breton (1930-2006) was a poet, journalist, literary critic, and French publisher. Born in Avignon, Breton later went on to manage the magazines Les Hommes sans shoulders (1953) and Poésie 1 (1967). He also founded the publishing firm Les éditions Saint-Germain-des-Prés (1966), and became the director of the publishing house Cherche midi in 1978. The Breton manuscript collection reflects the 1961-1975 period of Breton's career during which he worked for these latter publishing houses and produced a range of poems and correspondence. Breton published and wrote letters to several notable French figures over the years, some of which are included within this collection: in particular, Jean Orizet and Serge Brindeau.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
The Breton mss. II, 1946-, consist of literary works acquired through Jean Breton, proprietor of the firm of Librairie Saint-Germain-Des-Pres in Paris. Some of the writings are accompanied by letters and related materials.
Related Material
Breton mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1981
French Literature; French poetry --20th century.; French Poetry--20th century--History and criticism; French literature--foreign countries; Breton, Jean
- 1969-1973, Burine, Claude de. Le passeur. (Bound 2)
- Box 1
  - 1962-1968, Joubert, Jean. Corps désarmé à la merci des arbres. Part A: Terre... (Box 1)
  - 1962-1968, Joubert, Jean. Corps désarmé à la merci des arbres. Part B: Oniriques. (Box 1)
  - 1962-1968, Joubert, Jean. Corps désarmé à la merci des arbres. Part C: Corps... (Box 1)
  - 1967, August 4, Han, Françoise. L'Espace Ouvert. (Box 1)
  - 1967-1969, Miège, Denise. Sous Les Pavés La Plage: Drafts. (Box 1)
  - 1967-1969, Miège, Denise. Sous Les Pavés La Plage: Proofs. (Box 1)
  - 1968, November 7 - 1970, March 5, Grappe, Denise. Bois de Memoire. (Box 1)
  - 1970, May 29 - 1972, May 30, Caraire, Andrée. Nos bourreaux s'endorment... (Box 1)
  - 1971, December - 1973, December, Colombani, Henry. Le sablier flambe. (Box 1)
  - 1972, May - October, Orizet, Jean. Les Grandes Baleines bleues. (Box 1)
  - 1973, Godeau, Georges Leon. Le Fond des Choses. (Box 1)
  - 1974, June, Rivet, Jean. Livre d'un long silence. (Box 1)
  - 1974, June 2, Rivet, Jean. Neige Obscure. (Box 1)
  - Undated, Bertrand, Michel Edouard. Nos Cris Vraiment Nus. (Box 1)
  - Undated, Bourg, Maurice. Saissons qui portez tout. (Box 1)
  - Undated, Murail, Gérard. L'arbre à sels: digne et douzane and Naissance de Venus. (Box 1)
  - Undated, Puel, Gaston. La voix des pronoms. (Box 1)
  - Undated, Vilmorin, Louise de. Carnet de Route. (Box 1)
- 1948 - 1949, March 10, Le coupable innocent. (Foliobox 19)
- [1967], Guibert. Marbres en Alyscamps. (Bound 1)
- 1946, June 30 - 1947, March 25, Morel, Robert. Vou Aurez. (Foliobox 3)
- 1967-1970, January, Thieck, Françoise. Fragments. (Foliobox 3)
- 1972, August 30, Champigny, Robert Jean. L'Analyse. (Foliobox 3)
- 1976, April 21, Debbenedetti, Jean Marc and Maurice André Laurent. Je dors sans doute en ce moment... (Foliobox 24)
- Undated, Barbier, Elisabeth. Le Jour ni L'Heure. (Foliobox 3)